Sari Sadiya, PhD

Email: sari.sadiya [at] gmail.com Schedule a Meeting: calendly.com/sari-sadiya/30min

Professional Summary

R2 researcher at Frankfurt Goethe Universität. Dual PhD in Computer Science and Cognitive Neuroscience with a strong background in Mathematics. Previously a VLSI engineer at Apple. My work focuses on machine learning applications for neuroscience, bioinformatics, and computer vision.

Beside research, I am a project director at an education nonprofit, and moonlight as a cellist.

EXPERIENCE

• Machine Learning Consultant

- Jience (2024): Implemented a recommendation system for a hiring platform.
 Tech stack: Next.js, Flask, Python, MongoDB, Weaviate, Google Cloud Functions.
- Aneesi.ai (2023): (pre-seed) Designed and implemented an LLM-based personalized b2b marketing agent.
 The company went on to acquire pre-seed funding.
 Tech stack: React, Flask, Python, Firestore, Weaviate, SQL, Google Cloud Functions.
- GamerTag (2023): (post series-A) Implement a embedding-based recommender system. Tech stack: Python, Zilliz, AWS

• Frankfurt Institute for Advanced Studies at Goethe Universität Frankfurt am Main, Germany

- Research Associate: Deep learning for computer vision and bioinformatics.
- o Course Instructor: Taught 4 semesters of "Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence Seminar".
- Thesis Supervisor: Mentored 8 junior researchers, resulting several conference publications.

• Michigan State University

Michigan, USA

- Course Instructor and Teaching Assistant (2019-2020): Supervised 3 Independent Study Projects. Lectured and wrote assignments and for *Introduction to Programming* and *Introduction to AI*.
- Research Assistant (2015-2018): Developed conversational robot learning from demonstration systems.

• **\(\psi\)** Apple Inc.

Haifa Matam Center, Israel

Website: sari-saba-sadiya.github.io

LinkedIn: sari-saba-sadiya-a3993365

• VLSI Engineer (2013 -2015): Circuit design and verification with Verilog and System Verilog Assertions.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Machine Learning: Extensive experience in training and fine-tuning convolutional and transformer-based models. Tech Stack: PyTorch, Sklearn, Numpy, Pandas, OpenCV, Slurm, MLflow, Hadoop, C++
- Cloud Applications: Proficient in deploying machine learning models using various cloud services. Tech Stack: Cloud Firestore, Weaviate, AWS Sagemaker, Docker, Google Cloud Functions
- Full Stack Development: I build accessible frontends to deliver ML products to users. Tech Stack: NextJS, restfulAPIs, VueJS, Bootstrap, PWA, PyQt, Flask, MongoDB, SQL
- Experimental Psychology: Designing and conducting behavioral, eye-tracking, EEG, and fMRI experiments. Coding and Statistical Analysis: *Matlab, FreeSurfer, EEGLAB, PsychoPy, E-Prime, SPSS*
- Hardware and Embedded Development: Former Engineer at Apple. Tech Stack: Verilog and System Verilog Assertions, x86 Assembly

EDUCATION

Dual PhD in Computer Science and Cognitive Neuroscience

Michigan State University

Academic advisers Dr. Ghassemi (CSE) and Dr. Liu (PSY)

Aug. 2017 - Dec. 2022

Thesis Title: Machine Learning Approaches for Processing and Decoding Attention Modulation of Sensory Representations from EEG

MSc Computer Science (Sponsored by the Fulbright program)

Michigan State University

Academic adviser Dr. Joyce Chai (now at University of Michigan)

Aug. 2015 - May. 2017

Final Project: Interactive Human-Robot One-Shot Task Structure Learning from Demonstration

BSc Mathematics

Final GPA 3.6

Technion - Israel Institute of Technology

Dec. 2009 - Apr. 2013

BSc Computer Science

Final GPA 3.6

Technion - Israel Institute of Technology

Dec. 2009 - Apr. 2013

LANGUAGES

• English: Full professional fluency (C1 equivalent Toefl score)

• German: Elementary proficiency

Arabic: NativeHebrew: Native

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Particularly interesting past publications. Joint first authorship with students I supervised is marked by *. For a full list of papers please see my Google Scholar Profile.

- Corr 2024: L. Khun*, S. Sadiya*, Jörg Schlötterer, Christin Seifert, Gemma Roig; Efficient Unsupervised Shortcut Learning Detection and Mitigation in Transformers Manuscript under review
- BIBM 2023: T. Ettling*, S. Sadiya*, G. Roig; Different Algorithms (Might) Uncover Different Patterns: A Brain-Age Prediction Case Study In Proceedings of the 2023 IEEE International Conference on Bioinformatics and Biomedicine (BIBM)
- ICASSP 2022: S. Sadiya, T. Alhanai, M. Ghassemi;

Feature Imitating Networks

In Proceedings of the 2022 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP)

- NER 2021: **S. Sadiya**, T. Alhanai, M. Ghassemi; Artifact Detection and Correction in EEG data: A Review In Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE International Conference on Neural Engineering (NER).
- Frontiers 2020: S. Sadiya, T. Alhanai, T. Liu, M. Ghassemi; Unsupervised EEG Artifact Detection and Correction. In Frontiers in Digital Health. Volume 2.

INVITED TALKS AND WORKSHOPS

- Cutting Gardens 2023: S. Sadiya, D. Bersch, G. Roig Net2Brain: Unraveling Cognitive Functionality as Captured by EEG Using Pretrained Neural Networks
- Conference on Cognitive Computational Neuroscience 2023: S. Sadiya, A. Gifford, M. Vilas The Algonauts Hackathon: Predicting Brain Responses to Images with Pretrained Neural Networks.

Awards & Honors

•	Dissertation Completion Fellowship Support for Students completing their dissertation, from the Graduate School at MSU. Total value: 5,416\$	2021
•	Cultural Heritage Informatics Fellowship Researching digital methods and computational approaches for cultural informatics. Total value: 4,000\$	2020
•	Graduate Office Fellowship Awarded to graduate students as a summer assistantship. Total value: 6,942\$	2020
•	Fulbright Scholarship program for international educational exchange Full Scholarship, Granted by the U.S. Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs. Total value: 30,000\$	2015
•	Dean Honour List, Technion - Israeli Institute for Technology. Top 10% of students in the program	2013

Additional Experience

Project director for the Refugee Outreach Collective "Global Classroom", a partnership with Central Michigan University. The project expands educational access to individuals experiencing displacement at Malawi Dzelaka refugee camp through participation in accredited online classes.